Pujari: Now the names of Lord Vishnu. Om Shri Keshavaya Namah,
Pujari: Maintenant les noms du Seigneur Vishnu. Om Shri Keshavaya Namaha,
Om Shri Narayanaya Namah, Om Shri Madhavaya Namah,
Om Shri Narayanaya Namaha, Om Shri Madhavaya Namaha,
Om Shri Govindaya Namah, Om Shri Vishnuve Namah,
Om Shri Govindaya Namaha, Om Shri Vishnuve Namaha,
Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah, Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah,
Om Shri Madhusudanaya Namaha, Om Shri Trivikramaya Namaha,
Om Shri Vamanaya Namah, Om Shri Shridharaya Namah,
Om Shri Vamanaya Namaha, Om Shri Shridharaya Namaha,
Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah, Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah,
Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namaha, Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namaha,
Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah, Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah,
Om Shri Vasudevaya Namaha, Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namaha,
Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah, Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah,
Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namaha, Om Shri Purushottamaya Namaha,
Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah, Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah,
Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namaha, Om Shri Narasimhaya Namaha,
Om Shri Achyutaya Namah, Om Shri Janardanaya Namah,
Om Shri Achyutaya Namaha, Om Shri Janardanaya Namaha,
Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah, Om Shri Damodaraya Namah,
Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namaha, Om Shri Damodaraya Namaha,
Om Shri Upendraya Namah, Om Shri Haraye Namah,
Om Shri Upendraya Namaha, Om Shri Haraye Namaha,
Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Om Shri Krishnaye Namaha.
Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devi Namoh Namaha.
Shri Mataji: Why these twenty-one names are taken before every puja,
Shri Mataji : Pourquoi ces vingt et un noms sont-ils dits avant chaque puja,
even before the today renovation of it?
avant même la rénovation actuelle de celle-ci ?
First you have to worship Shri Ganesha.
D'abord, vous devez vénérer Shri Ganesha.
But even before worshipping why these names are taken,
Mais même avant de vénérer, pourquoi ces noms sont dits,
is important to understand, everything has a why.
il est important de le comprendre. Tout a un pourquoi.
Because these are the twenty-one channels within your Sushumna,
Parce que ce sont les vingt et un canaux de votre Sushumna,
twenty-one channels, we should say, in this
vingt et un canaux, nous devrions dire, dans
complete Ida, Pingala and Sushumna Nadi.
cet Ida complet, Pingala et Sushumna Nadi.
So to raise you,
Donc pour vous élever,
absolutely to give you the ascent,
pour absolument vous donner l'élévation,
twenty- one channels in Ida, Pingala, Sushumna.
vingt et un canaux en Ida, Pingala, Sushumna.
So one would say seven channels in the Sushumna Nadi.
On pourrait donc dire sept canaux dans le Sushumna Nadi.
But these seven channels are divided multiplied by seven into three.
Mais ces sept canaux sont divisés en trois fois sept.
So every channel has got twenty-one (inner? Unclear) channels.
Donc, chaque canal a vingt et un canaux (intérieurs ? Incompréhensible).
So Sushumna Nadi has got also twenty-one channels.
Donc le Sushumna Nadi a aussi vingt et une canaux.
Left-hand side Nadis are as you know that –
Les Nadis de gauche sont comme vous le savez
perhaps you know, I don’t know if you know the names or not.
- peut-être savez-vous, je ne sais pas si vous connaissez les noms ou non.
And the right hand side also, like Gayatri,
Et le côté droit aussi, comme Gayatri,
Parvati and all these are on the righ hand side.
Parvati et tous ceux-là sont sur le côté droit.
And the left ones are called as Chamundi,
Et les gauches s'appellent Chamundi,
and all these left-sided things, there are seven of them.
et tous ceux du côté gauche, il y en a sept.
Now, the central path has got twenty-one channels
Maintenant, le chemin central a vingt et un canaux
and has got twenty-one powers.
et a vingt et un pouvoirs.
And their deities are named
Et leurs divinités sont nommées
according to the twenty-one aspects of Shri Vishnu.
d'après les vingt et un aspects de Shri Vishnu.
And that’s why these twenty-one aspects are first said,
Et c'est pourquoi ces vingt et un aspects sont d'abord dits,
so that within you all these twenty-one channels are awakened.
de sorte qu'en vous tous ces vingt et un canaux sont éveillés.
Within you, first of all.
En vous, tout d'abord.
Puja is a double thing, that a cup has to be made
La Puja est un double aspect, qu'une coupe doit être fabriquée
and then this source has to be opened out.
et qu'ensuite cette source doit être ouverte.
So you are the cup.
Vous êtes donc la coupe.
The Sushumna is the channel you have by which you suck in.
La Sushumna est le canal par lequel vous aspirez.
So to open the Sushumna these twenty-one names are said.
Ainsi, pour ouvrir la Sushumna, on dit ces vingt et un noms.
Now, why first Shri Ganesha?
Pourquoi d'abord Shri Ganesha ?
Because Shri Ganesha is the beginning of the desire.
Parce que Shri Ganesha est le commencement du désir.
And the end of the desire.
Et la fin du désir.
You start with Ganesha and end up with Ganesha.
Vous commencez avec Ganesha et vous finissez avec Ganesha.
And that’s why Shri Ganesha is worshipped.
Et c'est pourquoi Shri Ganesha est vénéré.
Is the other way round now, the source.
Dans le sens inverse maintenant, la source.
When you direct your attention to the source you worship it,
Quand vous dirigez votre attention vers la source, vous l'adorez,
and when you want to incite or open out your own being,
et quand vous voulez inciter ou ouvrir votre propre être,
then you chant it.
alors vous la chantez.
This is the difference between worship and a mantra.
C'est la différence entre vénération et mantra.
If you just say mantra, you open yourself up.
Si vous dites juste un mantra, vous vous ouvrez.
But when you worship and chant, then you tap the source.
Mais quand vous vénérez et chantez, alors vous puisez à la source.
I don’t know if I’ve said this before or not.
Je ne sais pas si Je l'ai déjà dit.
Yogi: No, no, no. Shri Mataji: No? All right.
Yogi : Non, non, non. Shri Mataji : Non ? D'accord, c'est bon.
That’s how you understand the puja part.
C'est comme ça que vous comprenez la partie de la puja.
Now, those who are newcomers, their cup is completely useless.
Maintenant, ceux qui sont nouveaux, leur coupe est complètement inutile.
And when you excite the deities, they get busy opening their cups,
Et quand vous excitez les divinités, elles s'affairent à ouvrir leurs coupes,
everybody’s cups also. So it’s a double work.
les coupes de tout le monde aussi. C'est donc un double travail.
But if your cup is ready, it’s very easy to fill in.
Mais si votre tasse est prête, c'est très facile à remplir.
So now these twenty-one names I think you should take again
Donc maintenant ces vingt et un noms que je pense que vous devriez les redire
with the understanding, is better. All right.
avec la compréhension, c'est mieux. D'accord, c'est bon.
Pujari: Om Shri Keshavaya Namah, Om Shri Narayanaya Namah,
Pujari: Om Shri Keshavaya Namah, Om Shri Narayanaya Namah,
Om Shri Madhavaya Namah, Om Shri Govindaya Namah,
Om Shri Madhavaya Namah, Om Shri Govindaya Namah,
Om Shri Vishnuve Namah, Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah,
Om Shri Vishnuve Namah, Om Shri Madhusudanaya Namah,
Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah, Om Shri Vamanaya Namah,
Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah, Om Shri Vamanaya Namah,
Om Shri Shridharaya Namah, Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah,
Om Shri Shridharaya Namah, Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah,
Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah, Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah,
Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah, Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah,
Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah, Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah,
Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah, Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah,
Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah, Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah,
Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah, Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah,
Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah, Om Shri Achyutaya Namah,
Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah, Om Shri Achyutaya Namah,
Om Shri Janardanaya Namah, Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah,
Om Shri Janardanaya Namah, Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah,
Om Shri Damodaraya Namah, Om Shri Upendraya Namah,
Om Shri Damodaraya Namah, Om Shri Upendraya Namah,
Om Shri Haraye Namah, Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Om Shri Haraye Namah, Om Shri Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Pujari e gli yogi: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Pujari and Yogis: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devi Namoh Namaha.